Mitty knows that just when you thought you had your body all figured out,
bam, perimenopause. Suddenly, your hormones are raging like it's puberty round two.
You're waking up at 3 a.m. and dealing with mood swings that have mood swings.
Your ears are itchy, your jeans don't fit, you need an industrial-sized band to cool down,
and you've suddenly forgotten the word for microwave.
Most women in perimenopause don't know that they are,
even though it can last for 10 years. They also don't realize that most of their symptoms
are treatable. That's why we built Mitty Health. Mitty is a company built by women who've been
through it. Our menopause experts actually listen and treat the real symptoms you're feeling.
Your symptoms aren't just common, they're treatable. Schedule a visit with a menopause
specialist at Mitty. Visit joinmidi.com. Specialist-led care, virtual visits,
insurance-eligible. Midlife needs Mitty. Results may vary. Medications prescribed only
if clinically appropriate based on a consultation with a clinician. Ensures coverage varies. Check
with your plan for coverage. Back to school is busy enough. The last thing you need is
shopping that makes it harder. Whether you're moving into a dorm, your first department,
or just getting organized for the semester, Wayfair makes it easy to get everything you
need in one place. Furniture, bedding, storage, decor, study essentials, all at prices
you'll love with fast shipping before move-in day. Get everything you need for back-to-school season.
Shop Wayfair.com today. Wayfair, every style, every home.
This isn't the end of a fight. It's the start of one.
Lioness, the critically acclaimed original series from Taylor Sheridan returns August
2nd only on Paramount+. In the new season, hidden networks, foreign operatives, and personal
betrayals collide. Meanwhile, Joe walks the line between duty and family as unseen forces
circle her world, leaving her to reckon with the war that now reaches into every part of her life.
Don't miss the new season of Lioness, starring Zoe Saldana, Michael Kelly, with Morgan Freeman
and Nicole Kidman, streaming August 2nd only on Paramount+. This isn't the end of a fight.
It's the start of one. Lioness, the critically acclaimed original series from Taylor
Sheridan, is now streaming only on Paramount+. In the new season, hidden networks, foreign operatives,
and personal betrayals collide. Meanwhile, Joe walks the line between duty and family as unseen
forces circle her world, leaving her to reckon with the war that now reaches into every part
of her life. Don't miss the new season of Lioness, starring Zoe Saldana, Michael Kelly,
with Morgan Freeman and Nicole Kidman, now streaming only on Paramount+.
On the issue of friends, what's important is not just your actual friends in prison.
Another thing that's important is the number of people whom you meet and with whom you are
friend Lee. I had this core of friends in prison, but there was another two dozen prisoners,
with whom I was friend Lee. Right before I left for prison, one of my lead attorneys,
Mark McDougal, said something to me that was critically important. He pulled me aside and he
said, the CIA is very angry that you received such a light sentence. They're going to do
something to set you up, so be aware at all times that you're being watched.
I go to prison. I'm there for about six weeks and one of the prisoners with whom I was friend
Lee was an Afghan American pharmacist who unfortunately had an oxy problem. He was doing,
I think it was seven years for trafficking an oxy cotton. He came up to me one day
and he said, hey John, there's a new prisoner who wants to meet you. He's the spokesman for the
Taliban. I said, the spokesman for the Taliban? He said, yeah. I said, are you talking about
that case in New Jersey, where this Afghan guy claimed to be the Taliban representative
in the United States? Yeah, that's the case. I said, yeah, I followed that case.
No, I'm not interested in meeting this guy. He said, oh, okay, I'll tell him.
A few days later, I'm walking around the track like I did every day. A man is walking toward me
with a beard down to his waist and his arm outstretched to shake my hand. I immediately
knew this was the guy who professed to be the Taliban spokesman and I put my hands up in the
air like a person would be surrendering just so my hands could be seen. And I said, stop.
And he says, come on, man, I just wanted to say hi and introduce myself. And I said,
don't fucking touch me. And just as I said that, I looked just past him and I saw one of the guards
in the woods outside the fence with a camera with a long telephoto lens going click, click,
click, click, click, click, click, click. He wanted me to shake this guy's hand, maybe embrace him
so he could send the pictures to the FBI and the FBI could then accuse me of colluding with the
Taliban or planning some attack or something. And I said, again, don't fucking touch me as
God is my witness. I will kill you. Come on, don't be like that. I'm not going to say it
again. Get the fuck out of my face. And then he backed off. Well, guess what?
He was only in our prison for five days. They specifically transferred him in there
to set me up on another charge. It didn't work. And they transferred him out.
Everybody in the administration objected to me writing letters from Loretto. The warden
objected because I was embarrassing him that he was running essentially an organized crime
outfit from the prison. The CIA hated it because remember the whole point of prosecuting me was to
silence me. And instead they made me famous and gave me a voice. I was a whistleblower. No one who
is corrupt likes whistleblowers where they thought that this was going to just silence me.
Instead it emboldened me. I'm John Kiriakou. Welcome to Dead Drop. What makes a spy tick?
This is episode nine in our series doing time like a spy. We thank you as always for listening
and especially when you like, rate, review, or comment on the podcast on whatever platform you
call home. Speaking for myself, I can't imagine anyone aspiring to become a whistleblower. It
is not a shortcut to leading an easy life. But once you've made the choice and it is a choice
one makes, you can't imagine not seeing it through because if you, the whistleblower,
don't, all that corruption on which you're blowing the whistle will steep and get exponentially worse.
Hopefully you've made this choice to blow the whistle because you can't abide corruption.
The thought of corruption or corrupt politics makes you physically ill. In the outside world
there's plenty of corruption but most of it is pretty well hidden or it's been normalized.
In the prison world, by contrast, most of it's right out in the open.
You don't need anything more than functioning eyes and ears to see it, hear it, and know that it's
real. If Loretto had been the one corrupt prison run by the Bureau of Prisons, that still would
have been cause for concern. But much of Loretto's corruption flowed from top to bottom. The
corruption at Loretto was working in concert with the corruption at other prisons and
within the BOP itself. Sure, plenty of people cry corruption from within the prison system
about the prison system. I had receipts and plenty of them courtesy of the BOP.
By sending this Afghan to set me up, it just proved my position that they were a criminal
organization. Whether it's the CIA or the FBI or the BOP or the DOJ, they're all criminals.
I tell people all the time, the FBI doesn't get promoted by not arresting you.
Justice Department prosecutors don't get promoted by not prosecuting you.
They all see themselves some day as the U.S. Attorney or a member of Congress or running
for governor or sitting in the big corner office in some A-list law firm. They don't
get there by not prosecuting you. My distributor for letters from Loretto was at first my attorney,
Jessalyn Radak, and Jessalyn would send them to Jane Hampshire at a news website called
Fire Dog Lake. Fire Dog Lake was progressive and Jane was friendly with Ariana Huffington,
the founder and owner at the time of the Huffington Post. Jane would publish the letters
from Loretto first and they would be immediately like within an hour picked up by the Huffington Post.
They would spread like wildfire first among the independent media or the progressive media,
and then the mainstream media. The progressive media was funny, meaning it sort of depends on
how progressive we're talking. The real progressive media, the transparency proponents,
the anti-espionage act proponents, they were all in. But the pretend fake progressive media,
like MSNBC, and that awful, horrible Rachel Maddow as one example, they saw me as a troublemaker.
Remember, it was the Obama administration that prosecuted me. It was John Brennan that
insisted that I be sent to prison. The funny thing too is, I've always considered myself to be a
progressive, although I believe very strongly that the ideological spectrum is not a straight line
from left to right. It's a circle. And at some point on every issue, it meets. I'm a regular
on Fox News. I count some of the most important conservative commentators as close friends.
There's a lot we disagree on, but there's a lot we agree on too. And I am very, very happy to work
with people with whom I can agree, and I don't care what their political beliefs are. Unless they're
like lunatics or Holocaust deniers or something, I'm very happy to work across lines. And that's
why I consider myself to be an independent, independent. I'm not at all tied to either
of the two parties. If anything, I consider myself to be a libertarian. Ronald Reagan once said,
government is the problem. It's not the solution to the problem. And on so many issues,
that's right. Now, I want there to be a strong social security system. I want there to be
universal healthcare. Healthcare is a human right. Everybody should have healthcare equally.
But at the same time, I want the government out of my business.
We have too much regulation. We are over-legislated. When we have 5% of the world's population and
25% of the world's prison population, we have a very serious problem. We incarcerate more people
than China. And they have three times more people than we do. That's not right. I was
determined to get those ideas out there into the mainstream. I wanted Americans to be debating
them and discussing them. And lo and behold, that's exactly what happened. The unit manager,
who was one of the very few people that I didn't hate, decent guy, I don't remember his name
oddly enough. I don't remember any of their names. It must be some kind of psychological
defense mechanism. But I don't remember any of their names. He came up to me and he said,
hey, I want to warn you, they're gunning for you. I said, who is? And he said, the warden,
the assistant warden, a couple of the other unit managers. I said, I'm not afraid of them.
And he said, I'm just telling you because you might want to take measures to protect yourself.
And so that's what I did. When I would write a letter from Loretto, I wouldn't leave it in my
locker. I would immediately put it in an envelope, address the envelope to Juslin,
put legal mail on the front and the back and walk down to the mailroom so that it was out
and they could not intercept it. When my cousin Kip came in and gave me that intelligence
that the reason I wasn't in solitary was because I hadn't mentioned anybody's name,
I knew then that I could say anything I wanted and there was nothing they could do about it.
They asked me to stop repeatedly and finally I said again to the unit manager, I said,
you know what? I'm willing to stop. But you need to do something for me. I'm eligible for six
months of halfway house time, six months. Technically, I was eligible to get out of
prison at something like 17 months. Actually, it was exactly 17 months. And I said,
I will stop writing if you put me in for the maximum amount of time in the halfway house.
The halfway house because I'm educated, because I had a support system, because I could easily
get a job, I would have been in the halfway house a day or two and then they would have
sent me home and converted the halfway house time to home confinement. So that was the plan.
And he said, okay, I said, I'm trusting you here. And he said, okay, I'll do it.
And so I stopped writing for a period of months. I just stopped writing. And then I went to the
cafeteria one day for lunch and the unit manager was standing there, something that
they called call outline for some reason that I never understood. He said to me, hey, that
thing you and I agreed to, he said, it's not going to happen. I said, it's not going to
happen. You promised me. He said, I asked for it. They said, no, it's not going to happen.
I ate as fast as I could and went straight to the phone and called my wife and told her,
in fact, I said on the phone, these degenerate liars, and that's the term that I used,
these degenerate liars were nicked on the deal. She was devastated. So was I.
And immediately the unit manager called me in. Like I say, he was a decent guy. He was a reasonable guy.
And he said, I knew you would be upset. So I was listening to your call to your wife.
You called me a degenerate liar. And I said, you are, you looked me in the eye and you lied to me.
You knew that they wouldn't approve it, but you didn't want me to write. You're a degenerate
liar, just like all the rest of them. And he said, I could put you in solitary for that.
And I said, when are you guys going to understand? I'm not afraid of your solitary. I don't care.
Go ahead, put me in solitary. Believe me, it's going to be a lot worse for you than it is for me.
And he backed off. I decided that day I was going to write letters from Loretto regularly
and I was going to point out all of the corruption, all of the official thievery
that I possibly could. And that's when I really started rolling.
That afternoon, I went back to my cell to write my next letter from Loretto,
which I intended as a thank you note to those who had helped me.
I also intended this to be a direct challenge to the warden.
I'm going to skip the thank yous. I thank a lot of people in this letter from Loretto.
Here's the rest of it. January 20, 2014.
Hello, everybody. I'm sorry I've been out of touch so long.
After my last letter, I thought I had come to an understanding with the prison administration.
Stop writing letters from Loretto and be put in for nine months of halfway house.
Nine months would have seen me leave here on August 1, 2014.
So I stopped writing. I withdrew two formal complaints against staff
and I turned down all press interviews. In the end, I was put in for six months of halfway house,
not nine, and I was warned that the six months could be reduced to three or to nothing.
Rather than twiddle my thumbs and hope for the best, I decided to start writing again.
God bless the Constitution and its First Amendment.
Just as an aside, I ended up getting no halfway house time at all, not a single day.
I thought that when I was denied the nine months that the easiest thing to do was to roll over and
accept it. Maybe I would be released on November 1, 2014, maybe February 1, 2015,
but as more time passed, I realized that the situation is political in nature.
I realized further that if I just gave up, I would never forgive myself.
Breakdowns are preventable. MaintainX helps you catch the failure before it happens,
with easy to manage preventative maintenance and work orders that can be created and assigned in
seconds. No binders, no excel, no scramble. Companies on MaintainX have cut unplanned
downtime by over 30%. Try it free at maintainx.com.
Back to school is busy enough. The last thing you need is shopping that makes it harder.
Whether you're moving into a dorm, your first apartment, or just getting organized for the semester,
Wayfair makes it easy to get everything you need in one place. Furniture, bedding, storage, decor,
study essentials, all at prices you'll love with fast shipping before move-in day.
Get everything you need for back-to-school season. Shop Wayfair.com today.
If you're enjoying Dead Drop and, of course, we hope you are,
then while you're waiting for new episodes, I'd like to suggest another great granular story
podcast from the Costard and Touchstone family. Just the photographer with David Swanson does for
photojournalism what Dead Drop does for spies. Pulitzer Prize-winning photojournalist David
Swanson tells you stories his amazing news photos just can't. What it felt like being in all
those dangerous places like war zones and natural disasters, doing his job taking pictures.
Having been to a few war zones myself, I can tell you this. Just the photographer will put you
right there, on the ground, right next to David. Inside his head, in fact, it's a hell of a podcast
and you can find it wherever you find your favorite podcasts or at costardandtouchstone.com.
There's a link in this episode's show notes. In fact, you'll find lots of great story
podcasts at Costard and Touchstone. Like The Donor, A DNA Horror Story, The Hall Closet, Sage
Wellness Within, and The How Not to Make a Movie Podcast. Who knows, your next favorite podcast
might be just a click away. Now back to Dead Drop. I followed that up less than two weeks later
with another letter from Loretto. February 2, 2014. High again from the Federal Correctional
Institution at Loretto, Pennsylvania. The term Federal Correctional Institution implies that the
government is in some way correcting the behavior of prisoners here. In truth, that's just a bad
joke. Nothing is corrected at Loretto. There's no therapy to help anybody with problems,
except if you're a drug addict nearing the end of your sentence. More on that in a minute.
Pedophiles get no psychological therapy whatsoever. And the only classes offered by
staff are GED prep courses and English as a second language classes for the 400 or so illegal
aliens serving drug sentences. After completion of their sentences, then deportation,
knowing English will make it easier for them to then re-enter the US to restart their
criminal enterprises. If you already have a high school diploma, tough luck. Here's how things
work. We all get good conduct time, a maximum of 47 days off our sentences for every year
of incarceration. Congress actually mandated 52 days a year, but the Bureau of Prisons told Congress
to go screw itself. The only incentive to behave properly is a negative one, so you don't lose
your good time. You get no tangible benefit from taking any classes taught by prisoners,
creative writing, introduction to Spanish, and history of Western film to name a few.
The only way to actually collect your good time is to either get your GED
to be working on it or to not get into trouble. Everybody with the drug case wants to get into
the drug program. If you're accepted and you had no violence or firearms in your case,
you're sent to the nearest prison that hosts the program and you must complete 500 hours of
classroom work. If you complete the coursework, you can get up to one year off your sentence.
The pre-course drug class is supposed to be 40 hours. It's actually about 10 hours and is
comprised only of watching episodes of the A&E show intervention. If you're a drug addict and you
come to prison, you have to get off drugs cold turkey, then wait until you near the end of your
sentence to finally get into the drug program. That means you could wait 5, 10, even as long as
30 years before you get any drug counseling at all. Loretto's so-called education department
scheduled a prisoner-led class last fall called Quantum Physics. Nobody bothered to check
whether the prisoner teacher was qualified to teach a course on Quantum Physics,
nor did anyone request a lesson plan. As it turned out, the gay prisoner teacher's only degree was
from Ringling Brothers Barnum and Bailey Clown College. The course had nothing to do with
Quantum Physics. It was a self-help pity party for pedophiles and it sought to help them
expand their rationale of denial with the theme from Rocky playing in the background
all the while. The teacher began the course by chanting,
We're homos and we're chomos. We're homos and we're chomos.
Chomo, of course, being short for child molester. One African-American prisoner who expected to
actually learn something about Quantum Physics got up, shouted, This is fucked up, and walked
out. Otherwise, it was a very popular class among a certain demographic. I'm not kidding.
Even more worrisome is the situation with pedophiles in general. Despite a recent congressional
research service report to the contrary, there is no treatment whatsoever for pedophiles and child
molesters. Nothing. Indeed, these perverts find a welcoming community of like-minded defenders in
prison like we saw in the Quantum Physics class. They also trade pictures of children
that they cut out of the Toys R Us catalog or parenting magazine, photos of young-looking
18-year-olds in G-strings that they buy from mail order houses that cater to sex offenders in prison,
and even pictures of other inmates' children. Stolen, of course. Pedophiles move in packs
in prison. They sit together in the cafeteria. They take prisoner-led classes together. They
watch movies together, and they congregate in large groups in the library and the chapel,
all protesting their innocence and complaining that they're misunderstood.
My friend, cellmate, and former colleague Dave and I took a prisoner-led Introductory Spanish class
a few months ago. We quit after three sessions because the class was nothing more than a coffee
clatch for pedophiles. After one asked, how do you say in Spanish, do you want some candy?
We walked out and never went back. The Bureau of Prisons doesn't do anything
to dissuade pedophiles. Indeed, in an event right out of the Twilight Zone,
the warden sent a memo to all inmates, quote, please join FCI Loretto and the Bureau of Prisons
as we celebrate the United Nations Universal Children's Day, unquote. The memo announcing,
Happy Children's Day, said, quote, our Children's Day celebration will be held on the weekend
of November 30 to December 1, 2013. Materials will be available for each family with visiting
children ages three to 10, unquote. So we have a facility where pedophiles and pedarasts are
warehouse, where they get no therapy or medication for their perversion, where they spend all their
time together exchanging tricks of the trade, and where the warden gives them advance
warning of a children's event so they can schedule their own visits and be in the
presence of young children from 8.30 AM to 2.15 PM over two days. You may recall from my
third letter from Loretto that a prison guard had to move my entire family during a visit because
that pedarast Schaefer from Philadelphia was leering at my nine-year-old son. I'll say it again,
if pedophiles must stay more than 1,000 feet from a school on the outside, why are they allowed
within five feet of my children in the visitor's room? Even though I haven't been able to
take or at least complete any classes since I got to prison, I have learned a lot.
Among the things one can learn are how to cook methamphetamine,
how to smuggle drugs across international borders without getting caught,
how to steal food from the cafeteria and then cook an entire meal using only a live
electrical wire and a garbage can full of water, how to make contraband cigarettes
using chewing tobacco spat out by the prison guards, dried, and rolled with toilet paper,
how to self-medicate using home remedies and over-the-counter concoctions in lieu of
real medical care, how to set up a Ponzi scheme and how to defraud mortgage
companies and the Department of Housing and Urban Development, which was another prisoner-lit class.
So at the end of the day, I guess I have been educated in prison.
Maybe I have been corrected. I'm confident now that I'm ready to reenter civilized society.
Seriously though, this lack of counseling, rehabilitation, and educational and training
opportunities for prisoners is a long-term problem for society. The country is already home to an
increasingly large population of uneducated, untrained, unreformed, pissed-off ex-felons who
are not going to just sit around hoping to win the lottery. Lacking prospects for employment,
they'll do what they do best, commit crimes. For the pedophiles, they will leave prison
emboldened by the fact that they spent their entire sentence among like-minded sickos without
once being challenged about their perversions. The B.O.P. needs to get on the ball. Yours, John.
Yeah, I'm surprised that I got as much negative feedback on that letter as I did.
There were a lot of people who told me that as a progressive, I should be ashamed of myself,
that I don't support pedophiles re-enduring society. And I just doubled down like, no,
that's not going to happen. Eight days later, I decided to write yet another letter from Loretto.
I was on a roll. Hello again from the Federal Correctional Institution at Loretto, Pennsylvania.
On February 7th, I gave my first press interview since the prison administration
reneged on our halfway house deal. They would put me in for nine months halfway house,
and I would stop writing letters from Loretto, decline all media interviews,
and withdraw two formal complaints against staff. As you know from my previous letters,
that agreement is no longer in effect. And so on the 7th, I spoke at length with Dean Sirigos
and Dimitrios Tsakas of the National Herald, the oldest, largest, and most highly respected
Greek American newspaper in the country. We spent more than two hours together,
and we discussed issues ranging from halfway house time to terrorism, drones, and Afghanistan.
The journalists had gone through the formal approval process weeks in advance,
were approved, and arrived during normal business hours as instructed.
Three hours after the interview ended, I was sitting in the TV room with my friend,
former colleague and cellmate Dave, when another prisoner approached us and said,
guys, the cops are tearing up your room. We walked back to our room and sure enough,
two corrections officers were going through all of our possessions. I thought it was an odd
coincidence, but I just shrugged. I didn't have any contraband, so I lost nothing.
The very next night, Dave and I went for a walk around the outdoor basketball court.
When we walked back into the housing unit, another prisoner approached us and said,
hey, the cops are tearing you guys up again. We couldn't get to our cubicle because the
gate at the head of the hall was locked. A half hour later, the COs opened it and allowed
us back in. This shakedown was different than the previous days, and I should note that
in the previous year, I had been shaken down a total of three times until the interview.
My locker door was left wide open. My cellmate's lockers were all closed and locked.
Photos of my children were thrown all over the floor. My mail was strewn all over my bed,
and my books were tossed on a nearby chair. I approached the CO and complained.
Retaliation is one thing, but this was just plain disrespectful.
Sorry, was the response. We were just following orders.
My cellmates were also disrespected. This shakedown was very thorough,
and they had all lost property. One of my cellmates, a 40-ish African American whom I like,
respect, and consider a friend made an important point. He said,
don't you see what they're doing? They're trying to make us mad with these shakedowns
so that we'll turn on you. He imagined a conversation. Let's piss off the big black
guy so he pressures Kiryaku to stop writing and doing interviews.
My cellmate urged me to keep up the fight. He said,
keep telling people what it's like in here. I promise to do that.
The issue here is not the bother and inconvenience of shakedowns.
The COs are within their rights to shake us down whenever they want.
The issue is retaliation and censorship, which are illegal.
Back to school is busy enough. The last thing you need is shopping that makes it
harder. Whether you're moving into a dorm, your first apartment,
or just getting organized for the semester, Wayfair makes it easy to get everything
you need in one place. Furniture, bedding, storage, decor, study essentials,
all at prices you'll love with fast shipping before move-in day.
Get everything you need for back-to-school season. Shop Wayfair.com today.
Wayfair, every style, every home.
Your line just went down. The scramble starts. Clipboards, binders, phone calls,
every minute down costs money, and most unplanned breakdowns are preventable.
MaintainX helps you catch the failure before it happens, with easy-to-manage
preventative maintenance and work orders that can be created and assigned in seconds.
No binders, no excel, no scramble. Companies on MaintainX have cut unplanned downtime
by over 30%. Try it free at MaintainX.com.
A senior prison official told me months ago that there have been
active discussions about putting me in diesel therapy for the rest of my sentence.
Diesel therapy is when a prisoner is transferred from one prison to another all across the country
via prison van, bus, or con-air plane, never staying in any one prison long enough to receive
telephone, email, mailing, or visitation privileges. I could move to a different prison
every week for the rest of my sentence and still not hit them all. In the meantime,
my family and attorneys wouldn't even know what time zone I was in. This would obviously be
retaliation for letters from Loretto and my press interviews, but the BOP could easily
make up a lie that it was related to a bed space issue or perhaps for my own safety.
Still, it would stink of retaliation for the exercise of my constitutional right to freedom of
speech. I'm fortunate that my attorneys, among Washington's best, are willing to sue individual
BOP employees as well as the BOP as an organization to ensure that such an assault on my rights
doesn't take place. BOP officials should keep in mind what the Supreme Court said about diesel
therapy in the case of Frazier v. Dubois. Section 1210 transfers. Although prisoners enjoy no
constitutional right to remain in a particular institution, prison officials do not have discretion
to punish an inmate for exercising his First Amendment rights by transferring him to a different
institution. Frazier v. Dubois, 1990. Similarly, I have a constitutional right against retaliation
as the Supreme Court set forth in Block v. Rybar and in Scoog v. County of Clackamas.
Section 460, retaliation. Plaintiffs had a First Amendment right to criticize a public official's
performance of his duties and in action alleging retaliation by official against
plaintiffs due to their exercise of their First Amendment rights, it was insufficient for
them to allege injury in form of embarrassment, humiliation, and emotional distress.
Right exists to be free of police action for which retaliation is but for cause,
even if probable cause exists for that action. These cases are freely available in the Prison
Law Library. Perhaps prison officials should acquaint themselves with them. Maybe they could
also look up Largent v. Texas, which prohibits censorship. Section 306, censorship.
Any regulation which makes dissemination of ideas depend upon approval of distributor by official
constitutes administrative censorship in extreme form and subject to certain exceptions. Any
regulation which subjects communications to license infringes right of free speech,
Largent v. Texas. Where do we go from here? First, understand that any monolithic bureaucracy
will tend toward corruption without proper oversight. There is an internal administrative
remedy process that's a joke. You write a complaint and they tell you to go screw yourself.
Calling for an inspector general investigation is also a joke. An inspector general could make an
entire career investigating where the money from the inmate trust fund goes. Where did that
new flat screen TV and the CO medical lounge, especially during federal budget sequestration
come from? The only alternative is to go to the top. BOP director Charles Samuels. Director Samuels
worked his way up after starting as a line CO, moving up through the ranks to Warden and then
onto Washington to lead the BOP. Certainly he knows the difference between right and wrong.
Certainly he wouldn't want his employees to violate the law, as I've documented in these
letters. Certainly he wouldn't want his people's actions highlighted in a press investigation.
So join me in writing director Samuels and in demanding an end to these
illegal and unconstitutional actions by his staff. We have to put our foot down and say
enough. I'll let you know how things develop. Best regards, John.
I added a post script to this letter from Loretto. It says this.
I wanted to thank representative Jim Moran, Democrat of Virginia, who sent a second letter
to director Samuels last week saying, quote, As you will recall, I sent a letter last September
requesting that the Department of Justice grant my constituent, John Kiriaku, at least nine months
of halfway house time. Despite the fact that 12 months of halfway house time is well within BOP
guidelines, I am disappointed to learn that John's return to society may be unnecessarily
delayed. Thus, I am writing to reiterate the importance of John's release to a halfway
house as soon as possible, so that he can be a father to his five children and resume
productive contributions to society, unquote. Representative Moran is a 12 term congressman
and a member of the House Appropriations Committee, which controls the BOP budget.
Addendum about 12 hours after I wrote this letter from Loretto, I was called to the
special investigative service office. The CEO there handed me an envelope containing the
first 20,000 words of this book. I hadn't even realized it was missing since the shakedown.
The SIS CEO said that the CIO who had shaken me down had determined that the manuscript
had, quote, made threats against staff, unquote. He said he too had read it and believed that
it did not contain any threats to staff. The allegation was patently absurd in any event.
He returned it to me in its entirety, although he almost certainly made a copy.
In one last swipe at my civil rights and my constitutional right to freedom of speech,
the shakedown CEO tried to remove my desk from the wall and to confiscate it. After all, if I
have no desk, I can't write letters from Loretto, right? After a while he gave up,
the bolts were stripped and wouldn't budge. I had stripped them on purpose as a preemptive
measure. It was a temporary respite though. The CEO issued a work order to chip it
off the wall. I had to go to the unit manager who promised me that the desk would not be removed.
It wasn't. These crude, amateurish attempts to deprive me of my rights don't originate with a
low-level CEO. They come from higher up, from officials who should know better. But I have
the Constitution in my corner and I won't stop fighting. After my letter was published,
I taped a page from a legal pad on the desk and I wrote on it,
This desk kills fascism. This was a play on this machine kills fascism, which folksinger Woody Guthrie
had famously written on his guitar in the 1930s. The sign hung up on the desk for only a couple of
hours before a CEO tore it down, crumpled it into a ball, and threw it on the floor.
I picked it up and mailed it home to myself. I keep it as a reminder that I was not alone
as I went through this experience. Outside Loretto, America was beginning to more fully
reckon with the terrible things that had been done on our collective behalf.
The Senate is notoriously deliberative and slow. But as I fought the corruption inherent in my
punishment, the US Senate was about to address the corruption that punished me.
Remember that famous Nietzsche quote I referenced a few episodes back about staring into the
abyss and becoming the monster? Well the good news was I could almost begin to see the
light at the end of this Godforsaken tunnel and for a change it wasn't an oncoming train.
But what had survival cost me inside my head? Inside my soul? We've got so much more story
to tell in the episodes ahead. We will get into the Senate's report on torture. It doesn't turn
out well for the CIA. But in the next two episodes we're going to talk about rules
and about food. Breaking the rules in prison and strangest part of all enjoying
some of the food there, all while doing time like a spy. Until next time, I'm John Kiriakou.
Dead Drop is written by John Kiriakou and Alan Katz. Costart and Touchstone Productions produces
the podcast and John Kiriakou, Alan Katz and Nick Mechanic are its executive producers.
This podcast, it's a Costart and Touchstone production.
Back to school is busy enough. The last thing you need is shopping that makes it harder.
Whether you're moving into a dorm, your first department, or just getting organized for the
semester, Wayfair makes it easy to get everything you need in one place. Furniture, bedding, storage,
decor, study essentials, all at prices you'll love with fast shipping before move-in day.
Get everything you need for back to school season. Shop Wayfair.com today.
I'm Jake Stouck, co-founder and CEO of Serval. We built Serval to automate the
IT work that slows companies down. Onboarding, password resets, access to applications,
my laptop stopped working. While employees wait for help, their real work is put on hold.
IT desperately wants to automate this work and that's why they need Serval. You just tell Serval
what you want to automate in plain English and it's built. No drag and drop workflows,
no expensive consultants. Employees get unblocked and IT teams go from drowning in tickets to
building what actually matters. With Serval, IT becomes the AI engine powering the entire company.
This is a new way to run IT. We guarantee you'll automate 50% of all tickets
and we'll prove it to you in a free four-week pilot.
Go to serval.com slash tickets. That's S-E-R-V-A-L dot com slash tickets.
This message is brought to you by Colegard. If you recorded songs off the radio for a
mixed tape, it might be time to scream for colon cancer.
The Colegard test is non-invasive, requires no special prep or time off
and you start screening right from your home. It's just three simple steps.
Set up, sample, and ship. If you're 45 or older and at average risk,
ask your doctor about the Colegard test, available by prescription only.
Learn more or request a prescription at Colegard.com slash podcast.